<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollView</string>
    <string name="topic">
        Mission

To provide IT programmes of study at tertiary education level, of relevance and good quality which will meet the needs of the society.
To carry out research to support intellectual through innovation to the growth of Information and Communication Technology.
To provide training and professional services for continuous enhancement of knowledge, capacity building and community development.
The Gyalpozhing College of Information Technology (GCIT), officially inaugurated on 6th October 2017 is one of the integral colleges of the Royal University of Bhutan. The decision to establish Gyalpozhing College of Information Technology was made during the meeting held on February 2, 2017, at the Hon’ble Prime Minister’s Office. In line with the decision, the chairman of Tertiary Education Board issued executive order no. Ref No. MoE/EO/2017/4513 dated 20 February 2017 to establish the College. The college is 24 kilometers away from Mongar town stretching an area of 62 acres of land engulfed by lush green mountains. The university is one of the three new colleges established in Eastern Bhutan with the VISION to be the ‘Center of Excellence in Information Technology steeped in GNH values’. The college offers an undergraduate programme in Bachelors of Computer Applications, BSc in Computer Science and Bachelor of Science in Information Technology. The program is taught by qualified and dedicated local and expatriate faculty members. The methodology of “Learning by Doing” is a unique one adopted by GCIT. It aims at giving hands-on experience which helps the students understand the practical implementation aspects and the concepts associated with it.
    The invention of Braille marked a major turning point in the history of disability. The writing system of raised dots used by blind and visually impaired people was developed by Louis Braille in nineteenth-century France. In a society that did not value disabled people in general, blindness was particularly stigmatized, and lack of access to reading and writing was a significant barrier to social participation. The idea of tactile reading was not entirely new, but existing methods based on sighted systems were difficult to learn and use. As the first writing system designed for blind people’s needs, Braille was a groundbreaking new accessibility tool. It not only provided practical benefits, but also helped change the cultural status of blindness. This essay begins by discussing the situation of blind people in nineteenth-century Europe. It then describes the invention of Braille and the gradual process of its acceptance within blind education. Subsequently, it explores the wide-ranging effects of this invention on blind people’s social and cultural lives.


Writing the main body
The body of your essay is where you make arguments supporting your thesis, provide evidence, and develop your ideas. Its purpose is to present, interpret, and analyze the information and sources you have gathered to support your argument.

Length of the body text
The length of the body depends on the type of essay. On average, the body comprises 60–80% of your essay. For a high school essay, this could be just three paragraphs, but for a graduate school essay of 6,000 words, the body could take up 8–10 pages.

Paragraph structure
To give your essay a clear structure, it is important to organize it into paragraphs. Each paragraph should be centered around one main point or idea.

That idea is introduced in a topic sentence. The topic sentence should generally lead on from the previous paragraph and introduce the point to be made in this paragraph. Transition words can be used to create clear connections between sentences.

After the topic sentence, present evidence such as data, examples, or quotes from relevant sources. Be sure to interpret and explain the evidence, and show how it helps develop your overall argument.

Example of a paragraph from an essay
Lack of access to reading and writing put blind people at a serious disadvantage in nineteenth-century society. Text was one of the primary methods through which people engaged with culture, communicated with others, and accessed information; without a well-developed reading system that did not rely on sight, blind people were excluded from social participation (Weygand, 2009). While disabled people in general suffered from discrimination, blindness was widely viewed as the worst disability, and it was commonly believed that blind people were incapable of pursuing a profession or improving themselves through culture (Weygand, 2009). This demonstrates the importance of reading and writing to social status at the time: without access to text, it was considered impossible to fully participate in society. Blind people were excluded from the sighted world, but also entirely dependent on sighted people for information and education.


Writing the conclusion
The conclusion is the final paragraph of an essay. It should generally take up no more than 10–15% of the text. A strong essay conclusion:

Returns to your thesis
Ties together your main points
Shows why your argument matters
A great conclusion should finish with a memorable or impactful sentence that leaves the reader with a strong final impression.

What not to include in a conclusion
To make your essay’s conclusion as strong as possible, there are a few things you should avoid. The most common mistakes are:

Including new arguments or evidence
Undermining your arguments (e.g. “This is just one approach of many”)
Using concluding phrases like “To sum up…” or “In conclusion…”
Example of an essay conclusion
Braille paved the way for dramatic cultural changes in the way blind people were treated and the opportunities available to them. Louis Braille’s innovation was to reimagine existing reading systems from a blind perspective, and the success of this invention required sighted teachers to adapt to their students’ reality instead of the other way around. In this sense, Braille helped drive broader social changes in the status of blindness. New accessibility tools provide practical advantages to those who need them, but they can also change the perspectives and attitudes of those who do not.


Essay checklist
Checklist: Essay0 / 14
My essay follows the requirements of the assignment (topic and length).

My introduction sparks the reader’s interest and provides any necessary background information on the topic.

My introduction contains a thesis statement that states the focus and position of the essay.

I use paragraphs to structure the essay.

I use topic sentences to introduce each paragraph.

Each paragraph has a single focus and a clear connection to the thesis statement.

I make clear transitions between paragraphs and ideas.

My conclusion doesn’t just repeat my </string>
    <string name="textview">Royal University OF Bhutan</string>
    <string name="mission_to_provide_it_programmes_of_study_at_tertiary_education_level_of_relevance_and_good_quality_which_will_meet_the_needs_of_the_society_to_carry_out_research_to_support_intellectual_through_innovation_to_the_growth_of_information_and_communication_technology_to_provide_training_and_professional_services_for_continuous_enhancement_of_knowledge_capacity_building_and_community_development_the_gyalpozhing_college_of_information_technology_gcit_officially_inaugurated_on_6th_october_2017_is_one_of_the_integral_colleges_of_the_royal_university_of_bhutan_the_decision_to_establish_gyalpozhing_college_of_information_technology_was_made_during_the_meeting_held_on_february_2_2017_at_the_hon_ble_prime_minister_s_office_in_line_with_the_decision_the_chairman_of_tertiary_education_board_issued_executive_order_no_ref_no_moe_eo_2017_4513_dated_20_february_2017_to_establish_the_college_the_college_is_24_kilometers_away_from_mongar_town_stretching_an_area_of_62_acres_of_land_engulfed_by_lush_green_mountains_the_university_is_one_of_the_three_new_colleges_established_in_eastern_bhutan_with_the_vision_to_be_the_center_of_excellence_in_information_technology_steeped_in_gnh_values_the_college_offers_an_undergraduate_programme_in_bachelors_of_computer_applications_bsc_in_computer_science_and_bachelor_of_science_in_information_technology_the_program_is_taught_by_qualified_and_dedicated_local_and_expatriate_faculty_members_the_methodology_of_learning_by_doing_is_a_unique_one_adopted_by_gcit_it_aims_at_giving_hands_on_experience_which_helps_the_students_understand_the_practical_implementation_aspects_and_the_concepts_associated_with_it_the_invention_of_braille_marked_a_major_turning_point_in_the_history_of_disability_the_writing_system_of_raised_dots_used_by_blind_and_visually_impaired_people_was_developed_by_louis_braille_in_nineteenth_century_france_in_a_society_that_did_not_value_disabled_people_in_general_blindness_was_particularly_stigmatized_and_lack_of_access_to_reading_and_writing_was_a_significant_barrier_to_social_participation_the_idea_of_tactile_reading_was_not_entirely_new_but_existing_methods_based_on_sighted_systems_were_difficult_to_learn_and_use_as_the_first_writing_system_designed_for_blind_people_s_needs_braille_was_a_groundbreaking_new_accessibility_tool_it_not_only_provided_practical_benefits_but_also_helped_change_the_cultural_status_of_blindness_this_essay_begins_by_discussing_the_situation_of_blind_people_in_nineteenth_century_europe_it_then_describes_the_invention_of_braille_and_the_gradual_process_of_its_acceptance_within_blind_education_subsequently_it_explores_the_wide_ranging_effects_of_this_invention_on_blind_people_s_social_and_cultural_lives_writing_the_main_body_the_body_of_your_essay_is_where_you_make_arguments_supporting_your_thesis_provide_evidence_and_develop_your_ideas_its_purpose_is_to_present_interpret_and_analyze_the_information_and_sources_you_have_gathered_to_support_your_argument_length_of_the_body_text_the_length_of_the_body_depends_on_the_type_of_essay_on_average_the_body_comprises_60_80_of_your_essay_for_a_high_school_essay_this_could_be_just_three_paragraphs_but_for_a_graduate_school_essay_of_6_000_words_the_body_could_take_up_8_10_pages_paragraph_structure_to_give_your_essay_a_clear_structure_it_is_important_to_organize_it_into_paragraphs_each_paragraph_should_be_centered_around_one_main_point_or_idea_that_idea_is_introduced_in_a_topic_sentence_the_topic_sentence_should_generally_lead_on_from_the_previous_paragraph_and_introduce_the_point_to_be_made_in_this_paragraph_transition_words_can_be_used_to_create_clear_connections_between_sentences_after_the_topic_sentence_present_evidence_such_as_data_examples_or_quotes_from_relevant_sources_be_sure_to_interpret_and_explain_the_evidence_and_show_how_it_helps_develop_your_overall_argument_example_of_a_paragraph_from_an_essay_lack_of_access_to_reading_and_writing_put_blind_people_at_a_serious_disadvantage_in_nineteenth_century_society_text_was_one_of_the_primary_methods_through_which_people_engaged_with_culture_communicated_with_others_and_accessed_information_without_a_well_developed_reading_system_that_did_not_rely_on_sight_blind_people_were_excluded_from_social_participation_weygand_2009_while_disabled_people_in_general_suffered_from_discrimination_blindness_was_widely_viewed_as_the_worst_disability_and_it_was_commonly_believed_that_blind_people_were_incapable_of_pursuing_a_profession_or_improving_themselves_through_culture_weygand_2009_this_demonstrates_the_importance_of_reading_and_writing_to_social_status_at_the_time_without_access_to_text_it_was_considered_impossible_to_fully_participate_in_society_blind_people_were_excluded_from_the_sighted_world_but_also_entirely_dependent_on_sighted_people_for_information_and_education_writing_the_conclusion_the_conclusion_is_the_final_paragraph_of_an_essay_it_should_generally_take_up_no_more_than_10_15_of_the_text_a_strong_essay_conclusion_returns_to_your_thesis_ties_together_your_main_points_shows_why_your_argument_matters_a_great_conclusion_should_finish_with_a_memorable_or_impactful_sentence_that_leaves_the_reader_with_a_strong_final_impression_what_not_to_include_in_a_conclusion_to_make_your_essay_s_conclusion_as_strong_as_possible_there_are_a_few_things_you_should_avoid_the_most_common_mistakes_are_including_new_arguments_or_evidence_undermining_your_arguments_e_g_this_is_just_one_approach_of_many_using_concluding_phrases_like_to_sum_up_or_in_conclusion_example_of_an_essay_conclusion_braille_paved_the_way_for_dramatic_cultural_changes_in_the_way_blind_people_were_treated_and_the_opportunities_available_to_them_louis_braille_s_innovation_was_to_reimagine_existing_reading_systems_from_a_blind_perspective_and_the_success_of_this_invention_required_sighted_teachers_to_adapt_to_their_students_reality_instead_of_the_other_way_around_in_this_sense_braille_helped_drive_broader_social_changes_in_the_status_of_blindness_new_accessibility_tools_provide_practical_advantages_to_those_who_need_them_but_they_can_also_change_the_perspectives_and_attitudes_of_those_who_do_not_essay_checklist_checklist_essay0_14_my_essay_follows_the_requirements_of_the_assignment_topic_and_length_my_introduction_sparks_the_reader_s_interest_and_provides_any_necessary_background_information_on_the_topic_my_introduction_contains_a_thesis_statement_that_states_the_focus_and_position_of_the_essay_i_use_paragraphs_to_structure_the_essay_i_use_topic_sentences_to_introduce_each_paragraph_each_paragraph_has_a_single_focus_and_a_clear_connection_to_the_thesis_statement_i_make_clear_transitions_between_paragraphs_and_ideas">Mission To provide IT programmes of study at tertiary education level, of relevance and good quality which will meet the needs of the society. To carry out research to support intellectual through innovation to the growth of Information and Communication Technology. To provide training and professional services for continuous enhancement of knowledge, capacity building and community development. The Gyalpozhing College of Information Technology (GCIT), officially inaugurated on 6th October 2017 is one of the integral colleges of the Royal University of Bhutan. The decision to establish Gyalpozhing College of Information Technology was made during the meeting held on February 2, 2017, at the Hon’ble Prime Minister’s Office. In line with the decision, the chairman of Tertiary Education Board issued executive order no. Ref No. MoE/EO/2017/4513 dated 20 February 2017 to establish the College. The college is 24 kilometers away from Mongar town stretching an area of 62 acres of land engulfed by lush green mountains. The university is one of the three new colleges established in Eastern Bhutan with the VISION to be the ‘Center of Excellence in Information Technology steeped in GNH values’. The college offers an undergraduate programme in Bachelors of Computer Applications, BSc in Computer Science and Bachelor of Science in Information Technology. The program is taught by qualified and dedicated local and expatriate faculty members. The methodology of “Learning by Doing” is a unique one adopted by GCIT. It aims at giving hands-on experience which helps the students understand the practical implementation aspects and the concepts associated with it. The invention of Braille marked a major turning point in the history of disability. The writing system of raised dots used by blind and visually impaired people was developed by Louis Braille in nineteenth-century France. In a society that did not value disabled people in general, blindness was particularly stigmatized, and lack of access to reading and writing was a significant barrier to social participation. The idea of tactile reading was not entirely new, but existing methods based on sighted systems were difficult to learn and use. As the first writing system designed for blind people’s needs, Braille was a groundbreaking new accessibility tool. It not only provided practical benefits, but also helped change the cultural status of blindness. This essay begins by discussing the situation of blind people in nineteenth-century Europe. It then describes the invention of Braille and the gradual process of its acceptance within blind education. Subsequently, it explores the wide-ranging effects of this invention on blind people’s social and cultural lives. Writing the main body The body of your essay is where you make arguments supporting your thesis, provide evidence, and develop your ideas. Its purpose is to present, interpret, and analyze the information and sources you have gathered to support your argument. Length of the body text The length of the body depends on the type of essay. On average, the body comprises 60–80% of your essay. For a high school essay, this could be just three paragraphs, but for a graduate school essay of 6,000 words, the body could take up 8–10 pages. Paragraph structure To give your essay a clear structure, it is important to organize it into paragraphs. Each paragraph should be centered around one main point or idea. That idea is introduced in a topic sentence. The topic sentence should generally lead on from the previous paragraph and introduce the point to be made in this paragraph. Transition words can be used to create clear connections between sentences. After the topic sentence, present evidence such as data, examples, or quotes from relevant sources. Be sure to interpret and explain the evidence, and show how it helps develop your overall argument. Example of a paragraph from an essay Lack of access to reading and writing put blind people at a serious disadvantage in nineteenth-century society. Text was one of the primary methods through which people engaged with culture, communicated with others, and accessed information; without a well-developed reading system that did not rely on sight, blind people were excluded from social participation (Weygand, 2009). While disabled people in general suffered from discrimination, blindness was widely viewed as the worst disability, and it was commonly believed that blind people were incapable of pursuing a profession or improving themselves through culture (Weygand, 2009). This demonstrates the importance of reading and writing to social status at the time: without access to text, it was considered impossible to fully participate in society. Blind people were excluded from the sighted world, but also entirely dependent on sighted people for information and education. Writing the conclusion The conclusion is the final paragraph of an essay. It should generally take up no more than 10–15% of the text. A strong essay conclusion: Returns to your thesis Ties together your main points Shows why your argument matters A great conclusion should finish with a memorable or impactful sentence that leaves the reader with a strong final impression. What not to include in a conclusion To make your essay’s conclusion as strong as possible, there are a few things you should avoid. The most common mistakes are: Including new arguments or evidence Undermining your arguments (e.g. “This is just one approach of many”) Using concluding phrases like “To sum up…” or “In conclusion…” Example of an essay conclusion Braille paved the way for dramatic cultural changes in the way blind people were treated and the opportunities available to them. Louis Braille’s innovation was to reimagine existing reading systems from a blind perspective, and the success of this invention required sighted teachers to adapt to their students’ reality instead of the other way around. In this sense, Braille helped drive broader social changes in the status of blindness. New accessibility tools provide practical advantages to those who need them, but they can also change the perspectives and attitudes of those who do not. Essay checklist Checklist: Essay0 / 14 My essay follows the requirements of the assignment (topic and length). My introduction sparks the reader’s interest and provides any necessary background information on the topic. My introduction contains a thesis statement that states the focus and position of the essay. I use paragraphs to structure the essay. I use topic sentences to introduce each paragraph. Each paragraph has a single focus and a clear connection to the thesis statement. I make clear transitions between paragraphs and ideas.</string>

</resources>